Thank you.
Those fools braved Aqua
Laguna to get here.
They're determined, if nothing else.
Either that or they're just lucky.
Remember, we have permission
to kill this time.
But if we kill them, it'll be
over before we have any fun.
The drawbridge? Yeah.
The Franky family's trying to
get that under control right now.
Once they bring it down, we should be
able to get to the other side, no problem.
What a pain.
She's right there and
all we can do is wait.
Damn it.
What is her deal?
She must be hiding one hell of a secret.
Hey, Cape!
Here are your orders.
Kill the intruders, but only engage
them here at the Tower of Law!
My life and my promotion are the
most important things right now.
I have to be careful about this.
If I let all my underlings run off,
who's going to protect me
if something goes wrong?
Ah!
Stupid pirates!
You may act tough, but you don't know
what you're getting yourselves into!
Open your eyes! Come on!
You don't think you can
beat all of CP9, do you?
And what about the Gates of Justice?
You don't think you can open them, do you?
Even then, if things
go wrong, I have this!
The Golden Transponder Snail, giving me
the authority to wish you a Buster Call!
A Buster Call?
Yes, that's right.
I'm sure you remember its power well.
After all, it did destroy
your homeland 20 years ago.
What was it, Ohara?
Hard to recall the name since
it was wiped off the map.
Robin's homeland?
He's pissing me off.
There's no place left.
Nowhere for me to go or return to.
Anything but that!
I'm begging you!
Ooh, begging for mercy, I like that.
What's wrong?
You don't want me to
press this and annihilate
all your little friends
with a Buster Call?
Is that what you're saying?
You're insane.
If you push that button, do you
have any clue what will happen?
Of course I do.
This button will eliminate any chance your
friends possibly have of
leaving this island alive.
All it takes is one little press.
It couldn't be more simple.
If you think that you
don't understand a thing
are all those old memories
coming back to you now
Let's see.
Maybe I should press it after all.
It might be fun
I'm the one who makes
the demands here, wench?
You say Ohara was wiped off the map,
but your map doesn't show you the
lives of the people who lived there.
Your view of the world
is so distant and so
twisted that you've lost
sight of your humanity.
There's a limit to how much you could
sacrifice in the name of justice.
A Buster Call is going too far.
You can't use it to anything but that.
All right, get her!
Nice throw! Wow!
Yeah!
Bullseye!
Take that, Monster Girls!
You're so creepy!
Monster! Monster! Monster! Monster!
The Monster Girls hit me!
Yeah, I'll be sorry!
Hey, you!
My kids came home crying because
you hit them on the head.
What are you thinking, acting like that?
You stay away from them, you hear me?
Don't you have anything
to say for yourself?
You really are a little
monster, aren't you?
Hey, you come back here.
I'm not done talking with you yet.
Mommy, Mommy, what are we
having for dinner tonight?
Well, what would you like?
Um, um, rice omelette!
You sure like rice omelette, huh? Yep.
Then we'll pick up some
eggs on the way home, okay?
Okay!
Sorry I'm home so late.
Hello, is anyone there?
Aunt Roji?
To Robin, today...
As you must know, is my
little girl's birthday.
So the family is going out
for a special dinner tonight.
Just the three of us.
We left some bread out on the table,
so you can eat that for dinner.
Don't be too greedy with the jam.
When you're done eating, and before we
come back, I want you to do the dishes,
scrub the floors,
take the laundry inside,
and go straight to bed as soon as
you're finished with your chores.
Mommy, Mommy, what are we
having for dinner tonight?
Well, what would you like?
Um, um, rice omelet!
You sure like rice omelettes, huh? Yep!
Then we'll pick up some
eggs on the way home, okay?
Okay!
Oh look, here comes Robin.
Seems she's stopping by to return a book.
Everyone, get in place quick!
Hello?
Professor Clover?
I finished the book you lent me.
One, two...
Congratulations, Robin!
You're amazing, Robin.
A real genius.
We've got a cake for you, by the way.
Robin, that doctoral exam you took the
other day, you passed with a perfect score.
Or, from this day forward, you
are an official archeologist.
And since you're one of us now, we
can all work on our research together,
starting today.
Here, this proves that you're a scholar.
Wear it with pride.
It looks great on you, Robin.
We're so proud.
Now listen up.
You must understand what it means
to be an Ohara archeologist.
Right, I'm ready to learn.
Our knowledge,
in particular, comes from
the past And this library,
known as the Tree of Knowledge
Has stood for over 5,000 years
Collecting countless documents
and literature from every corner
of the world This is a treasure
for all humanity to share and
nourish for future generations
As the world's largest library,
knowledge is our pride and joy
Under the branches of this tree,
the finest archaeologists
from every sea have gathered
With this vast wealth of
information at our disposal,
there is no historical
mystery that cannot be solved.
Are you ready to join us? Yes, sir.
In that case,
I look forward to seeing
your research take form and
watching all the contributions
you will make to the world.
Professor, what I'd really like is to find
out what happened in the blank century.
No, you can't!
I strictly forbid it just
as I always have! Huh?
I don't get it.
If we want to solve the
mysteries of the world,
shouldn't we study the Poneglyphs
to find out what happened back then?
What?
How do you know about all that?
Did you use your powers to
peek on us in the basement?
I just...
Any attempt to decipher
or study the Poneglyphs is
considered a criminal act
by the world government.
I see.
So that's why you don't tell anybody.
That's why you study them
in the basement at night.
You were spying on us?
So how much do you know?
This is a very serious matter
we're dealing with here.
Explain yourself, Robin!
I know it's bad.
But even if I asked nicely, You
still wouldn't let me join you.
That's why I studied so hard
to become an archaeologist.
Because I thought then you would
finally treat me like everyone else.
I just wanted to learn.
Robin.
I know this is hard.
You've studied with all your heart.
And deserve to be called a scholar
as much as anyone else here.
However, you're also still a child.
If word gets out, Then every
one of us could be put to death.
Harsh as that sounds, It's
something we're willing to accept.
Since this became the law
of the world 800 years ago,
Countless scholars have lost their lives.
as many as there are stars in the sky.
But we can't stop now,
and I'll tell you why.
Of all the scholars who ever tried
to decipher the ancient texts,
we of Ohara are the only ones
who have met with any success.
For us, there is no turning back.
I swear on the Tree of Knowledge, if you
ever come close to the basement again,
you will be forbidden
from entering the library?
or conducting research with us.
You understand?
Robin!
I hate to say this, especially
now, but she's just like her mom.
It's only a matter of time before
she uncovers that secret, too.
Her mother, Olvia, was only
captured by Marines a few days ago.
But it's already clear
what fate she'll suffer.
Oh, my God.
Oh, water.
Water?
Perfect.
Guess I'm still alive after all.
I just wonder if she's okay, too.
Anyhow, thank you for your help.
But I gotta ask, is there a town or
village somewhere around here? Mm-hmm.
That's a shame.
I suppose bakers can't be choosers,
but a deserted island would
have been nice, you know?
you can stare all you want but ain't
nothing gonna happen as you can see
I hurt my legs so I'm staying put
least for the time being after I feel
a little better I'll build a raft
or something to get me out of here
this your first time seeing a giant
missy yeah I'll tell you one thing I
may be as big as those guys from
albath but i sure ain't as mean just
as sure as there are warlike giants
there's peaceful ones too i know this
is a long shot but i gotta ask anyway
when you get home you think maybe
you could uh not tell anyone that a
giant washed up on the beach okay sure
well that was too easy of course you're
gonna tell people i said i wouldn't
Yeah, you tellin' a fib.
Ain't no way a kid can
keep a secret this big.
Don't worry about it.
I'm not really interested in you.
Derishi?
What does that mean?
It don't mean a darn thing.
I'm just laughing.
That's the way you laugh?
You sure are a funny little girl.
You're the funny one.
I gotta admit, all my life people have
been telling me my laugh is silly.
But you, you're pretty
cute when you laugh.
You should do it more often.
And I say,
Anyhow, I go by the name Saul.
Jaguar D.
Saul, if you like.
D?
Yeah, I don't much know what it means.
But from what I hear, everyone in my
family has it for their middle name.
Anyways, what about you?
My name's Robin. I see.
Well, truth is, Robin, some guys
are chasing me down right now.
So, uh, if someone finds
me, I'm in trouble.
I said, I wouldn't tell!
Good.
Here's another one.
Mighty kind to you, Robin, but
you go ahead and take this one.
My stomach's pretty full as is.
As you can see, I caught
a real Wapol last night.
Well, I better get back
to work on that raft.
It should be done pretty
soon at this rate.
I don't mean to pry, but it seems like you
have an awful lot of time on your hands.
Not that I don't like your company.
You've been sticking with me for days.
Ain't your parents and friends
going to get suspicious?
I don't have any parents.
Actually, I do have a mom, but she set sail
for work years ago and never came back.
I don't even remember her face.
I'm sort of friends with the
archaeologists around here,
but they won't let me join in on their
research, so I don't know anymore.
The other kids say I'm creepy, so
even if I wanted to play with them,
I don't think that they'd let me.
Ah, so you have Devil Fruit powers, huh?
You aren't scared of me?
I used to sail all over the
Grand Line back in the day.
I've seen plenty of folks with
powers ton scarier than yours.
To be honest, I'm kind of
jealous of you little arm thing.
It looks pretty handy. Daddy!
Daddy!
That laugh of yours is
really weird. Daddy!
It don't matter if your laugh's weird.
All that really matters is when you laugh,
all of a sudden your problems disappear.
Why?
What do you mean, why?
Everyone knows you laugh when
you're having fun, right?
So if you're not having fun,
all you need to do is laugh,
and everything will work out just fine.
You're just a kid.
But it seems like you're
having a tough time.
When you're feeling down, just laugh.
There ain't nothing a
good laugh can't fix.
It seems awfully silly
to laugh when you're sad.
Don't knock until you try it. Here. Dad!
Do it just like that, and I'll
bet you'll feel better in a flash.
Not bad!
Now, with more gusto!
Now that's more like it!
This is Navy Headquarters here.
Once again, we're hoping we
can speak to Chief Spandine.
You heard him, Chief.
What now? Ignore them.
They probably just want a status report.
We'll contact them when we see the shore.
That's good enough.
Ohara, opera, oh whatever, who cares?
Why are they wasting my time making me
trek all the way out here to the West Blue,
huh?
Let's get this over with, then
get the hell out of this dump.
Hey, is it true we've got
a Navy ship on the island?
What?
I haven't heard about that.
Yeah, it must have
anchored here overnight.
Why would the Navy come here?
I know.
We're pretty remote.
Weird thing is, when people
went to look at the boat,
they didn't see any Marines there.
Wow, that is weird.
It was like a ghost ship, not
a single person to be found.
Come on, now you're just fooling with us.
Professor!
Professor Clover!
My goodness, did something happen?
I hope it's nothing to worry about,
but I just heard that there's a huge
Navy ship anchored at the seashore.
We should take precautions.
It might be an investigation.
Better let the other scholars know.
The raft is done! All right!
So you're leaving already?
Now what's with that face?
You put those puppy dog
eyes away, little missy.
Actually, I suppose my
raft could use a flag, huh?
Guess I'll just have to
stay a little bit longer.
I'll be darned.
So you're looking to
set out to sea too, huh?
My mom's been away from home for years
thanks to all her big
archaeological research.
But whenever she finally
comes back to the island,
I'm going to ask her to take
me along on her next trip.
That's why I've been studying so hard.
I got my archaeology
doctorate just like her.
You got a doctorate?
A tiny little girly like you? Mm-hmm.
But hold on a sec.
Didn't you tell me you don't even
remember what your mom's face looks like?
Yeah, but she's still my mom.
I want to see her.
Hey, Sol.
Did you know that our
world has a period of
100 years that nobody knows
anything about? Uh-huh.
I believe folks call that the
blank century, don't they?
I'm curious about it myself,
but the government says it's
illegal for anyone to look into.
That's right.
But I heard my mom is traveling all over
the world investigating it in secret.
it.
But don't tell anyone.
I don't want her to get in trouble.
What?
Are you telling me that your
mom's going around looking
for them ancient stone tablet
things they call poneglyphs?
You've heard about poneglyphs?
Yeah, but that ain't the point here, okay?
You can't go around
talking about this kind of
stuff in front of other
folks out of the blue.
And if your mama's out there looking
for them, You especially gotta be good.
Huh?
Is something wrong?
Robin, do you happen to
know your mother's name?
It's Olvia.
Nico Olvia.
You okay?
Robin is Olvia's daughter.
Wait, so does that mean I've
been on O 'Hara all this time?
Mm-hmm
Oh, that's terrible!
Oh, no!
Why did I end up on O 'Hara of all places?
This is no time to be
sitting around, Saul?
Robin Yes?
This may come as a shock,
but you gotta listen to me and
listen good Navy battleships are on
their way to O 'Hara right now They
may even be here already The Navy? Why?
They're going to wipe out every
last scholar on the island.
That can't be. No.
So listen, whatever
you do... You're lying.
You can't let those government
guys know you're a scholar.
You're lying.
You've got to promise me that, okay?
Stop lying to me!
It's true, I swear!
I wouldn't joke about
something this serious!
Get to town as quick as you can and
see if anything strange is going on.
I know it sounds crazy, but
your mom might be there too.
It's been a while, hasn't
it? It's Olya. You came back.
We heard news that you've
been captured by the Navy.
Don't tell me I came back on their ship.
I hate to have to tell you this as soon as
I return, but the news you heard is true.
It's not your fault.
We knew the government would set
its sights on Ohara eventually.
I'm not sure how much you know,
but the Poneglyph search team that set off
six years ago was
annihilated by the Marines.
Thirty-three researchers were killed.
I was the...
the only survivor.
Fortunately, I was only captured.
But I overheard the
Marines talking after they
had rummaged through the
search team's belongings.
They soon realized that
we all came from Ohara.
I won't make any excuses.
All of you are in danger because
of my carelessness. Stop it.
Thinking like that won't do any good.
Those who set out to sea and those who
stayed behind are all part of the same team.
After what happened, if anyone
should apologize, it's us.
We know how much you've suffered.
Professor.
For years now, the world government has
seen Ohara as a threat to their rule.
But all we can do is
believe in the truth of
history and its value to
all generations to come.
Be that as it may, they've put us
in quite a compromising position.
I just don't know how we're
going to get out of this one.
I admit,
it doesn't look good,
but we're fortunate to have discovered
this information when we did.
We know that the government is hunting
down all the scholars on the island.
So before they make it to the
library, we have to escape from Ohara.
You have a point.
This time I have a feeling we won't be
able to slip past their investigation.
like we have before.
And if they're committed to killing
us, they won't listen to reason either.
Then hurry up and run!
I'm sorry, Olvia.
I can't let myself escape and leave one
of mankind's greatest treasures behind.
You should know that.
Everyone else here feels
the same way. Yeah.
Are you sure?
We still don't know what the
government's gonna do when they get here.
But we do know if we run, we can't
protect all this precious knowledge.
We're not planning on dying here.
Don't worry.
More importantly, I know you have
something else weighing on your mind.
I can't.
It's too late for that.
Make up your mind, Olvia.
Are you going to board this ship or not?
If you want to stay with your daughter,
we'll settle your husband's
unfinished business for you.
No, I'm not turning back.
I'm a scholar of Ohara.
It's my duty to carry out the
will of those who came before me.
Forgive me, Robin.
I swear, I'll solve these mysteries
and come back to you someday.
Where's my mommy?
Where'd she go?
Your mom had to go out to sea for her job.
You'll be staying here with
us for a little while, okay?
That's enough!
If you don't shut up, I'll hit you!
Honey, stop it.
She's only two.
And so is our daughter.
Listen, I don't care if
she's your sister's child.
She's a burden.
This was a mistake.
Who's there?
What are you doing here?
I was...
I mean, I just...
I'm so sorry!
If you want to read a book, all
you have to do is ask, all right?
But I can't, because I
don't have any money.
Well, then, looks like you're in luck because
you can read everything here for free.
For free? Uh-huh.
After all, this library is the best in the
world. It is? Really? Sure is. Let's see.
Unless I'm mistaken,
you're Olvia's daughter.
You like to read books? Mm-hmm.
She looks just like you
did when you were that age.
And I'm proud to say she's
every bit as clever, too.
If she's safe, that's enough.
When I decided to join you,
I severed all bonds with her.
I can't let her become the
daughter of a criminal.
Bad news!
Another ship came!
With the world government's flag!
One of their high-ranked officials
coming all the way here to the West Blue?
My goodness.
It seems this is quite serious indeed.
All right, everyone, listen.
From now on, you and I are neither
colleagues nor acquaintances.
You have to stick to that no matter what.
Farewell.
Oh wait, what are you going to do?
All right.
Tell HQ we've arrived.
Let's move it.
I want to get this over with.
What a pain.
They better give me a promotion
when this crap is over. Hey.
I want you to hunt down.
on every sculler on the island
and must straighten them.
Yes, sir!
What's going on?
Some woman is running around with a gun!
This is an awful mess.
I'm sorry, Robin!
Vice Admiral Kuzan!
What is it?
We've been informed that CP-9's
Chief Spandine has arrived at Ohara.
So what?
Did you really have to wake me up?
Just to tell me that?! I'm sorry, sir!
I didn't say anything, I was bored.
I was looking for living
while I was living.
I was a single
light that I found.
I felt like I saw.
If you follow me, the
future will run away!
The future will not be settled.
Every time, every time, stop.
The smile and the tears will be filled.
As long as a dark night?